A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 6262-9286 FA739C
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Conference on "Le Fait Feminin" (Reports 007772), 1976 (Box 335)
  Women -- Congresses; Women -- Services for; Barber, Elinor G.; Saario, Terry; Ford Foundation. International Division
- IIEP seminar on inequalities in the development of education (Reports 007773), 1978 (Box 335)
  Inequalities in the Development of Education Seminar (1978 Nov. 27-30: Paris, France)
  Education, Higher; Barber, Elinor G.
- International Sociological Association meetings (Reports 007774), 1978 (Box 335)
  Memorandum to ID Committee on Women's Programs, dated September 11, 1978.
  International Sociological Association Meeting (1978 Aug. 13-18: Uppsala, Sweden)
  Women -- Research; Sex role -- Research; Barber, Elinor G.; Research Committee on Sex Roles International Sociological Association Meeting.
- Conference on equal pay and equal opportunity at Wellesley College (Reports 007775), 1978 (Box 336)
  Memorandum to International Division Committee on Women's Programs, dated May 17, 1978.
  Equal Pay and Equal Opportunity Policy for Women Conference(1978 May 1-4: Wellesley College)
  Equal pay for equal work -- Congresses; Pay equity -- Congresses; Labor policy -- United States -- Congresses; Manpower policy -- United States; Affirmative action programs -- United States; Family policy -- United States; Barber, Elinor G.; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation. Vice President
- National Women's Conference (Reports 007776), 1977 (Box 336)
  Memorandum to International Division Committee on Women, dated December 5, 1977.
  National Women's Conference (1977: Houston, Tex.)
  Women -- Congresses; Women -- Research; Barber, Elinor G.; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation. Vice President
- Visit to Radcliffe Institute (Reports 007777), 1975 (Box 336)
  Research on women -- United States; Women's rights -- United States; Feminism -- United States; Barber, Elinor G.; Saario, Terry; Radcliffe Institute
- Visit to Wellesley Center (Reports 007778), 1975 (Box 336)
  Memorandum to ID Committee on Women.
  Women in higher education -- United States; Women's rights -- United States; Women -- Education, Higher -- United States; Feminism -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States; Barber, Elinor G.; Saario, Terry; Wellesley College. Center for Research on Women
- AID Conference on Women in Development (Reports 007779), 1975 (Box 336)
  Memorandum to ID Committee on Women in Programs.
  AID Conference on Women in Development
  Women in development; Women's rights; Barber, Elinor G.; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Wellesley and Wingspread Conferences (Reports 007780), 1976 (Box 336)
  Wellesley Conference on Women and Development (1976: Wellesley University)
  Women in development -- United States; Women -- Education -- United States; Feminism -- United States; Women's rights -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States; Barber, Elinor G.
- Seminar on African women in rural development (Reports 007781), 1976 (Box 336)
  Memorandum to International Division Committee on Women, dated May 3, 1976.
  Seminar on African Women in Rural Development Overseas Liaison Committee
  Women in rural development -- Africa; Women in development -- Africa; Barber, Elinor G.; Overseas Liaison Committee Seminar on African Women in Rural Development
- Recommendation for "A" status: DAP for a women's program in Brazil (Reports 007782), 1980 (Box 336)
  Women's program -- Ford Foundation (Rio de Janeiro); Silverstein, Leni M.; Ford Foundation (Rio de Janeiro) Women's program.
- Seminario "A Mulher na Forca de Trabalho na America Latina": conclusiones y recomendaciones relativas a las fuentes de informacion necesarias para estudiar la participacion de la mujer en los mercados de trabajo en America Latina = Seminar on Women in t (Reports 007783), 1978 (Box 336)
  Conference held to study women's participation in the labor force in Latin America.
  Seminario a Mulher na Forca de Trabalho na America Latina (1978: Rio de Janeiro, Brazil)
  Women employees -- Latin America; Women -- Employment -- Latin America; Torrado, Susana; Instituto Universitário de Pesquisas do Rio de Janeiro; Seminario a Mulher na Forca de Trabalho na America Latina (1978: Rio de Janeiro, Brazil); Instituto Universitário de Pesquisas do Rio de Janeiro
- Sao Paulo trip notes, visit to Pro Mulher (Reports 007784), 1978 (Box 336)
  Memo to James A. Gardner, dated August 3, 1978.
  Public interest law -- Brazil; Gardner, James A., 1943-; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Meeting to discuss research on the status of women in Colombia, Venezuela, and Peru (Reports 007785), 1974 (Box 336)
  Memorandum to Bruce Carlson.
  Status of women -- Peru -- Colombia; Status of women -- Venezuela; Myers, Robert G.
- Progress report - affirmative action (Reports 007786), 1972
  Memorandum to McGeorge Bundy.
  Affirmative action programs -- Ford Foundation; Trottenberg, Arthur D., 1917-; Ford Foundation Affirmative action.
- Current activities in Population Statistics Office of the Registrar General (ORG) (Reports 007787), 1970 (Box 336)
  Developing Countries Program/South and Southeast Asia
  06400160
  Population research; Demography; Population education; Wells, H. Bradley (Henry Bradley), 1927-
- Employment of women and minorities on the professional staff (Reports 007788), 1972 (Box 336)
  Employment of women and minorities -- Ford Foundation; Trottenberg, Arthur D., 1917-; Ford Foundation Employment of women and minorities.
- The Percy Amendment (Reports 007789), 1974 (Box 336)
  Memorandum to heads, POICs, representatives.
  Women in development -- United States; Barber, Elinor G.; Germain, Adrienne; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Whither women and development? (Reports 007790), 1981 (Box 336)
  United States and International Affairs Program/Human Rights and Governance
  Women in development; Women's rights; Dunlop, Joan; Ford Foundation
- Survey of new feminist organizations: progress report (Reports 007791), 1975 (Box 336)
  Feminist organizations -- Surveys; Women's rights -- United States; Feminism -- United States; Carden, Maren Lockwood; Ford Foundation Program possibilities in women's rights.
- Language planning, language spread, and language change (Reports 007792), 1978 (Box 336)
  Prepared for Georgetown University Round Table on Languages and Linguistics, 1979.
  Language and languages -- Planning, spread, change; Cooper, Robert L. (Robert Leon), 1931-2012
- Movement and agencies of language spread: Wales and the Soviet Union compared (Reports 007793), 1978 (Box 336)
  Prepared for the Conference on Language Spread, Aberystwyth, Wales, Sept. 12-14, 1978.
  Language spread -- Wales and USSR; Lewis, E. Glyn
- Program in language education for the Middle East Region (Reports 007794), 1977 (Box 336)
  Memorandum to Guillaume de Spoelberch, dated February 7, 1977.
  7 leaves + attachment -- 28 cm.
  Language and languages -- Study and teaching -- Middle East; Linguistics -- Study and teaching -- Middle East; Linguists -- Middle East; Sociolinguistics -- Middle East; Haynes, Lilith M.; Tucker, G. Richard; Ford Foundation Program in language for the Middle East
- Proceedings: International Conference on the Methodology of Sociolinguistic Surveys (Reports 007796), 1975 (Box 336)
  "Conference proceedings [of conference held in Montreal, Canada, May 19-21, 1975] with a paper on Sociolinguistic surveys: state of the art." --T.p.
  45 p. - 28 cm.
  International Conference on Methodology of Sociolinguistic Surveys (1975 May 19-21: Montreal, Quebec)
  Sociolinguistics -- Methodology -- Congresses; Pool, Jonathan; Cooper, Robert L. (Robert Leon), 1931-2012; Barber, Elinor G.; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation. Vice President
- CIEFL Central Institute of English and Foreign Languages evaluation study (Reports 007797), 1974 (Box 336)
  Memorandum to Donald Taylor.
  Educational planning -- Evaluation; Language and languages -- Study and teaching; Fox, Melvin J.; Central Institute of English and Foreign Languages
- International studies at Cornell (Reports 007798), 1979 (Box 336)
  Memorandum to Elinor G. Barber and Warren Ilchman.
  International studies -- Cornell University; Schuman, Barry; Cornell University. Center for International Studies
- International studies review: visit to Harvard University: dinner with senior faculty (Reports 007799), 1979 (Box 336)
  International studies -- Harvard University; Barber/Ilchman international studies review -- Background material; Gaer, Felice D.; Harvard University. Committee on International and Regional Studies
- International studies review: meeting with Karl Deutsch, Chairman, Committee on International Studies and Stanfield Professor of International Peace, Harvard University (Reports 007800), 1979 (Box 336)
- Sex discrimination: the big new problem for boards (Reports 007802), 1973 (Box 336)
  Sex discrimination and public education; Public schools -- Sex discrimination; Saario, Terry
- Minutes of meeting December 6, 1974 with Esther Boserup (Reports 007803), 1975 (Box 336)
  Memorandum to Esther Boserup, J. Bresnan, W. Carmichael, R. Edwards, L. Hardin, V. Ruttan, A. Weisblatt
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Management; Germain, Adrienne
- The three year Master's program at the University of Nebraska: report on visit, January 9-10 (Reports 007804), 1967 (Box 336)
  Universities and colleges -- Nebraska -- Graduate work; Education, Higher; Parker, Thomas W.; University of Nebraska--Lincoln
- Toward a program of child development and child care in Latin America (Reports 007805), 1980 (Box 336)
  Child development -- Latin America; Ford Foundation (Latin Amercia) Program for Child Development and Care.
- Harijan wasti (Reports 007806), 1980 (Box 336)
  Education -- India; Rice, Marion J.
- Irrigation: making it useful for disadvantaged groups (Reports 007807), 1980 (Box 336)
  Irrigation Seminar-ADC/AUFS (1980 June 19-20: Salisbury, Conn.)
  Irrigation -- Social aspects -- Developing countries -- Congresses; Germain, Adrienne; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation. Vice President
- United Planning Organization, Washington D.C., February 13 (Reports 007808), 1968 (Box 336)
  06400183
  Urban renewal; City planning; Urban poverty; Blacks; Campbell, Clifford J.
- United Planning Organization, Washington, D.C., November 30 (Reports 007809), 1967 (Box 336)
- United Planning Organization, Washington, D.C., October 5 (Reports 007810), 1967 (Box 336)
- UPO Washington, D.C. visit March 16 through 19 (Reports 007811), 1966 (Box 336)
- Confidential report on the Department of AGronomy, Argentina National University of the South, Bahia Blanca, Argentina (Reports 007812), 1970 (Box 336)
  Office of the Vice President/Finance
  06400216
  National Unviersity of the South
  Comprehensive development of agricultural training, research, and extension at the universeity in Argentina.
  Agriculture -- Research -- Argentina; Agricultural extension work -- Argentina; Public universities and colleges -- Argentina -- Finance; Endowments -- Argentina -- Evaluation; McKell, C. M.; Harris, Lorin E., 1915-1992; Universidad Nacional del Sur
- Agricultural teaching and research at the National University of the South Bahia Blanca, Argentina: Purdue University (Reports 007813), 1971 (Box 336)
  Final report to the Ford Foundation
  Agricultural development projects -- Argentina; Templeton, William C., Jr.
- Education for regional planning in developing countries (Reports 007814), 1967 (Box 336)
  06400222
  Education -- Chile; Urbanization -- Chile; Poor -- Chile; Friedmann, John; Ford Foundation. Latin America and Caribbean
- A general theory of polarized development (Reports 007815), 1967 (Box 336)
  An attempt to formulate a general theory of the development process and regional planning.
  Institute Of International Education, Inc.
  Education -- Chile; Urbanization -- Chile; Regional planning -- Chile; Friedmann, John; Ford Foundation. Latin America and Caribbean; Ford Foundation. International Affairs; Institute of International Education, Inc.
- Report on visit to National Engineering University (Reports 007816), 1965 (Box 336)
  06400219
  10 p. + 2 p. supplement.
  Education, Higher -- Peru; Town, George R.
- Budget cuts revisited: An OLAC perspective on adjusting to reduced spending levels (Reports 007817), 1974 (Box 336)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Office management; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Finance; Carmichael, William D. (William Daniel), 1929-; Ford Foundation
- Memoranda re Argentina, 1966. (Reports 007818) (Box 336)
  Repressive regimes -- Argentina; Fundación Bariloche; Universidad de Buenos Aires
- Population Office activities, fiscal (Reports 007819), 1969 (Box 336)
  Population -- Program activities; Harkavy, Oscar
- Population Office activities, fiscal (Reports 007820), 1970 (Box 336)
- 1970-71 budget: the social sciences and population policy (Reports 007821) (Box 336)
  Budget -- International Division -- Population; Driver, Edwin D.
- Population at alternative budget levels (Reports 007822), 1974 (Box 336)
  Budget -- International Division -- Population; Ford Foundation. Population Office.
- Asia and the Pacific Program by (Reports 007823), 1974 (Box 336)
  Technical assistance -- Pacific Area; Technical assistance -- Asia; Endowments -- Pacific Area; Endowments -- Asia; Bresnan, John, 1927-2006; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Ford Foundation
- Budget reductions (Reports 007824), 1974 (Box 336)
  International relations -- Finance; Goodwin, Craufurd D. W.; Ford Foundation. Europe and International Affairs; Ford Foundation
- Options in education and culture (Reports 007825), 1974 (Box 336)
  Education -- Finance; Arts -- Finance; Ward, F. Champion, 1910-2007
- A single Foundation operation in education (Reports 007826), 1974 (Box 337)
  Program development -- Education; Education -- Program development; Ward, F. Champion, 1910-2007
- The careers of women Latin Americanists (Reports 007827), 1976 (Box 337)
  Draft copy - not for quotation without permission.
  37 p. + attachment.
  Women -- Latin America; Latin Americanists; Chaplin, David
- Income and expenditure expectations and their budgetary implications (Reports 007828), 1970 (Box 337)
  Office of the Treasuerer
  Budget information; Ford Foundation
- Population information (Reports 007829), 1966 (Box 337)
  Population research; Population assistance; Birth control; Harkavy, Oscar
- Report on the National Employment Service of India: end of tour report (Reports 007830), 1968 (Box 337)
  06400400
  Manpower planning -- India; Freeman, Homer J.
- Evaluacion de Equipamiento Comunitario (Reports 007831), 1966 (Box 337)
  In Spanish.
  38 p.
  Community development -- Chile; Housing -- Chile; Kennon, Paul; Ford Foundation. Latin America and Caribbean
- Study-travel tour of North American universities (Reports 007833), 1965 (Box 337)
  06400433
  4 p. but incomplete.
  Education, Higher -- North America; Universities and colleges -- North America; Williams, R. L. (Randolph Lambert)
- Memorandum on population-demography: 1964 meeting with representatives of the Association of Medical Faculties at University Del Valle (Reports 007834) (Box 337)
  PA64-4444.
  Population research -- Colombia; Population research -- Latin America; Saunders, Lyle
- Planning session on water use and management - Oct 23 (Reports 007835), 1980 (Box 337)
  Irrigation -- India; Water-supply -- India; Drinking water -- India; Germain, Adrienne; Weisblat, A. M. (Abraham M.); Ford Foundation. Planning session on water use and managment
- Request for "A" status for a supplemental DAP on research on women and development in the Andean Region and the Southern Cone (769-0825) (Reports 007836), 1979 (Box 337)
  Memorandum to Richard W. Dye.
  Women in development -- Andean Region Southern Cone; Flora, Cornelia Butler, 1943-
- The International Division's work on women's roles in development (Reports 007837), 1976 (Box 337)
  Memorandum to Elinor Barber and David Bell.
  Women in development; Women's rights; Feminism; Germain, Adrienne; Ford Foundation. International Division Women's DAP.
- The Ford Foundation and women (Reports 007838), 1976 (Box 337)
  African women -- Ford Foundation; Women -- Ford Foundation; Goodwillie, Susan; Ford Foundation and women
- Curriculum for professionals dealing with rural women (Reports 007839), 1980 (Box 337)
  Working Seminar: Collateral in Development (1980 Dec. 4-5: Spring Hill Conference Center)
  Women in development; Barber, Elinor G.
- Kenya - sex differences in education (Reports 007840), undated (Box 337, Reel R-9302)
  Sex differences in education -- Kenya; Zollner, Joy.
- Women in Francophone West Africa (Reports 007841), 1979 (Box 337)
  IF/Middle East and Africa
  Women in Francophone West Africa; McKee, Katharine
- Progress on Women's DAP and related developments (Reports 007842), 1979 (Box 337)
  Memorandum to Adrienne Germain.
  Women -- Services for -- Ford Foundation; McKee, Katharine; Ford Foundation
- Women contacts at Universities of Ibadan, Ife, and Lagos (Reports 007843), 1979 (Box 337)
  Women in academia -- Universities of Ibadan, Ife, Lagos; McKee, Katharine; Universities of Ibadan, Ife, Lagos
- The Association for the Study of Women in Africa (ASOWA) (Reports 007844), 1979 (Box 337)
  Women's rights -- Nigeria; Feminism -- Nigeria; McKee, Katharine; Association for the Study of Women in Africa Nigeria.
- Programming for women in the Middle East (Reports 007845), 1975 (Box 337)
  Memorandum to Betty Skolnick.
  Women -- Middle East; Ford Foundation programming for women -- Middle East; Pappas, Linda M.
- Women in Bangladesh (Reports 007846), 1973 (Box 337)
  Memorandum to Elinor Barber.
  Women -- Bangladesh; Zeidenstein, George
- Experiments in education for rural development (Reports 007847), 1975 (Box 337)
  Education for rural development -- India; Kale, Pratima, 1938-
- Research: prospects for program development (Reports 007848), 1976 (Box 337)
  Research on role of women -- Pakistan; Mayo, Molly R.; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Confidential impressions of International Seminar on Women, Islamabad, November 10-15 (Reports 007849), 1975 (Box 337)
  Memorandum to Dr. John Cool.
  International Seminar on Women's Participation in Development (1975 Nov. 10-15: Islamabad, Pakistan)
  Women in development -- Pakistan; Mayo, Molly R.; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Seminar on "Role and Status of Women", Pakistan Administrative Staff College, 29-31 October 1975. (Reports 007850) (Box 337)
  Seminar on "Role and Status of Women" (1975 Oct. 29-31: Pakistan Administrative Staff College)
  Women's roles -- Pakistan; Mayo, Molly R.
- Review of Foundation assistance for education research, planning and experimentation in Thailand (Reports 007851), 1980 (Box 337)
  Education -- Research -- Ford Foundation (Bangkok); Ford Foundation (Bangkok) Education research.
- Women participation in currently supported programs, projects and awards (Reports 007852), undated (Box 337)
  Women -- Services for -- Philippines; Women's rights -- Philippines; Del Castillo, Solita; Ford Foundation --(Manila) Women's programs
- Visit of Ms. Elinor G. Barber to the Philippines (Reports 007853), 1977 (Box 337)
  Memorandum to Dr. Ozzie G. Simmons.
  Sex differences in education -- Philippines; Rixhon, Gerard
- The educational correlates of occupational attainment: a Bangkok case study of large-scale organizations (an abstract) (Reports 007854), 1976 (Box 337)
  Educational correlates of occupational attainment -- Thailand -- Bangkok; Fry, Gerald W. (Gerald Walton), 1942-
- The Ford Foundation in Thailand (Reports 007855), 1977 (Box 337)
  3 leaves + attachment: tables -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Thailand; Endowments -- Thailand -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Note on irrigation and women (Reports 007856), 1981 (Box 337)
  Irrigation and women; Women and irrigation; Chambers, Robert, 1932-; Lenton, R. L.
- Visit to India and Indonesia (Reports 007857), 1981 (Box 337)
  Memorandum to Eugene S. Staples, Tom Kessinger.
  Women -- Education -- India; Women -- Education -- Indonesia; Women's rights; Feminism; Barber, Elinor G.; Ford Foundation. International Division
- History and conditions of female labor force participation in Colombia (Reports 007858), 1975 (Box 337)
  Summary of presentation at the Technical Workshop on the Population Impact of Colombian Programs and Policies - December 1-2, 1975 - Villa de Leyva, Colombia.
  Female labor force -- Colombia; León de Leal, Magdalena; López de Rodríguez, Cecilia
- Request for "A" status approval: delegated-authority project for research, training and applied projects relating to the position of women in Mexico and Central America (Reports 007859), 1980 (Box 337)
  PAPER Conference (1980 Mar. 20-22: New York, N.Y.)
  Women -- Mexico -- Congresses; Redclift, Nanneke; International Division Women
- The Brazilian Women's Program (Reports 007860), 1980 (Box 337)
  Women -- Services for -- Brazil; Barber, Elinor G.; Ford Foundation
- The Urban and Regional Development Advisory Program in Chile of the Ford Foundation: A review and an evaluation (Reports 007861), 1968 (Box 337)
  06490224
  Community development -- Chile; Housing -- Chile; Mallon, Richard D.; Sjoberg, Gideon; Wingo, Lowdon
- Support for emerging community development corporations (Reports 007862), 1983 (Box 337)
  Community development, Urban; Community development; Ford Foundation
- Evaluation of nutrition projects in Mexico (Reports 007863), 1983 (Box 337)
  Nutrition -- Mexico; Solimano, Giorgio
- Urban community development in Ahmedabad: a report updating earlier review by Mr. John Kennedy (Reports 007864), 1969 (Box 337)
  Review of a grant in Ahmedabad given to spur urban community development.
  06000368
  Ahmedabad Municipal Corporation
  18 p. + annex.
  Urbanization -- India; Urbanization -- India -- Ahmadabad; Community development, Urban -- India -- Ahmadabad; Chatterjee, Bishwa Bandhu, 1922-; Ahmadābād (India)
- A report on the urban community development projects in Delhi and Ahmedabad (Reports 007865), 1966 (Box 337)
  Result of an extensive study of the two programs of urban community development supported by the Foundation during the last ten years.
  Urbanization -- India -- Delhi (India); Urbanization -- India -- Ahmadabad; Community development, Urban -- India -- Delhi (India); Community development, Urban -- India -- Ahmedabad; Kennedy, J. P. (John Patrick), 1930-; Ahmadābād (India)
- Report as consultant to the Science Teaching Center: University of the Philippines, October 3 - November 4 (Reports 007866), 1966 (Box 337)
  06400486
  Science -- Study and teaching; Education -- Science; DeRose, James V.
- Discussions in Paris of research on women (Reports 007867), 1976 (Box 337)
  Memorandum to ID Committee on women's programs.
  Women in development -- France; Women's rights -- France; Barber, Elinor G.; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Some impressions of higher education in South America (Reports 007868), 1961 (Box 337)
  Education, Higher -- Research -- South America; McHenry, Dean Eugene, 1910-; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Review of Foundation-funded women's studies research centers (Reports 007869), 1980 (Box 337)
  *Release approved by author 8/86 (See reference card under "Knowles").
  Women's studies; Knowles, Marjorie Fine, 1939-
- The Three Year Master's Program at Washington University: report on visit, March 9 (Reports 007870), 1967 (Box 338)
  06300068
  Education, Higher; Master's programs; Parker, Thomas W.; Washington University (Saint Louis, Mo.)